Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ruddraarnab (LinkedIn) ruddra.com (Personal) careers.stackoverflow.com/ruddra (Portfolio) ruddra.com (Blog)

Top Skills

Python Django JavaScript

Languages

Bangla (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional) Japanese (Elementary)

Certifications

Python Core and Advanced
Varnish Basics
A Mini Course on Time Management
Effective Object Oriented
Programming
Getting Started with Varnish

Arnab Kumar Shil

Senior Software Engineer at Cefalo | Opensource Enthusiast | Python and JavaScript Developer

Summary

I am a full stack developer living in Dhaka, capital of Bangladesh. I have been working in the software industry for 5+ years. You can consider me as an open source enthusiast, passionate about software development, Non-windows user, team player, self motivated person who loves writing codes professionally, as well as a hobby.

I contribute to Stackoverflow, where I try to help out the community, also learn from them to keep my knowledge up to date. I have more than 15K reputations at the moment.

Experience

Cefalo

1 year 7 months

Senior Software Engineer January 2019 - Present Dhaka, Bangladesh

Software Engineer

October 2017 - December 2018 (1 year 3 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Working as remote consultant for NHST Media Group. I lead a small team to develop and oversea Python/Javascript based projects for NHST Global Team(Upstream, Recharge, Intrafish, Tradewinds). Part time DevOps, built CI/CD using Jenkins/Openshift, and also responsible for deploying and maintaining several projects in Openshift

Binate Solutions Ltd.
Software Engineer
October 2016 - September 2017 (1 year)
Mirpur DOHS, Dhaka, Bangladesh

I was responsible for several projects in there. What I had done so far:

- 1. Built a Scalable web application which consumes 3rd party API services and makes posts to multiple social media in real time, generates images and messages dynamically based on feed.
- 2. Worked on making features and extending of a betting platform called BetInfromed, added Image generation from charts using PhantomJs and Selenium.
- 3. Built an application based on WebRTC.
- 4. Worked on Core Project for It-button.com, extended its features. It's an Airbnb between software companies and clients.

I have served as project lead for multiple projects.

Technologies I have used:

Angularjs, JQuery, Django, Celery etc for the development, DRF for REST APIs. Also used Selenium, PhantomJs, PIL for image generation processes in serveral projects.

Followed SCRUM for software development.

Appdragon Ltd Software Engineer March 2015 - September 2016 (1 year 7 months) Dhaka, Bangladesh

I worked here mainly as Backend Developer. Mainly I worked on:

- 1. Worked on building new features and extending performance for scalable web applications which is a bulk SMS service called Phonix(which is used in http://smartmessage.me).
- 2. Worked on a subsidiary project which converted email to SMS; also supported bulk SMS sending services.
- 3. Built a test architecture using Postman
- 4. Worked on building a purging module for Phonix for optimized deletion process without hampering the service or triggering any downtime.

Technologies I have used:

Tornado, Django, Celery, SQLAlchemy, MySQL, Docker, Vagrant; consuming RESTful based web services and so on.

PROGmaatic Developer Network

1 year 7 months

Junior Software Engineer

October 2013 - February 2015 (1 year 5 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

This company is currently known as Field Information Solution GMBH.

I have worked on:

- 1. Worked on making e-commerce site for HYY E-commerce.
- 2. Worked with a small team to build a Sales and Distribution platform called Blackwidow which is the core product of the company. It was used to in making several sales and distribution for companies like Six Seasons, Jita, Crown Cement, Field Buzz etc.

Technologies I have used:

Django, PostgreSQL, Celery, JS/Jquery etc. and Django Rest Framework

Intern

August 2013 - September 2013 (2 months)

Education

Jahangirnagar University

Master of Science (M.Sc.), Computer Science and Engineering (2012 - 2013)

Jahangirnagar University

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Computer Science and

Engineering · (2008 - 2012)

Notre Dame College, Dhaka

H.S.C · (2006 - 2008)

Motijheel Govt. Boys' High School

S.S.C · (2001 - 2006)